TITLE: “…The Mysterious Lifeform.”
Account Book
Yomogi Preschool
Bazaar
Mysterious Lifeform
Yomogi Preschool
Bazaar
Welcome
Teru Teru Bozu
Next Episode
“…The Mysterious Lifeform, #2”
The leaves are falling again…
It’s going to be a lot of
trouble cleaning tomorrow.
Looks like they’re having trouble too.
Sayaka-sensei…
Is there anything I can do for them?
Kobato-san!
Welcome back!
I’m home!
You all went out together?
Yes. Their school held a bazaar.
Bazaar?
Everyone brings in a bunch of things.
Then they sell it and use the money for the school!
That’s it!
A bazaar!
Sayaka-sensei, let’s hold a bazaar!
We’ll sell a bunch of things and pay back the debt collector!
Kobato-chan…
If we pay off the debts, we won’t have to vacate this place anymore, right?
Right?
Let’s do a bazaar!
Kobato-chan, you see-
If we could pay off the debts with just that, we would’ve paid it off ages ago.
Fujimoto-san…
Even a big school would only get so much out of it,
let alone a little preschool with a small group of kindergarteners.
Running a bazaar won’t get us anywhere.
It’s not worth the effort.
I’m sorry!
I caused such a commotion.
I’ll go clean up outside.
If we were to actually run a bazaar and Kobato-chan saw how useless it was,
we’d end up feeling sorry for her.
I see why you’d want her to give up,
but saying it like that won’t do.
If you’re too blunt, you come off as a bully.
I…
I was the only one who was excited.
Fujimoto-san and Sayaka-sensei
were certainly surprised, weren’t they?
I’m such an idiot.
Well, the idiot part is true.
But I don’t think putting in true effort is bad.
Ioryogi-san!
Don’t hold onto me so much! You’re annoying!
Kobato-chan.
Sayaka-sensei.
Let’s do the bazaar!
Bazaar?
You bring in things you don’t need at home, or things that you’ve made,
and then we sell them at the preschool.
It’s like playing store-keeping!
I want to be a yakisoba seller!
That might be good too.
I’ve put the details into your communication booklets.
Be sure to show it to your families.
Okay!
Let’s do our best!
Fujimoto-kun.
It’s good that Kobato-chan cheered up.
I don’t care either way.
Bye-bye!
Sayaka-sensei, see you tomorrow!
Okay, bye!
Bazaar!
What is that?
A dog!
And that?
A cat!
Don’t you think it’s bad to
put dogs and cats together?
It’s true, so she can’t really say anything back.
Thanks for your work.
Thank you!
Did you draw this, Kobato-chan?
Yes!
It looks great!
This duck and sheep are really cute!
I’ll be leaving now.
Work?
Yes.
Don’t push yourself too hard.
I won’t.
You too.
Don’t push yourself too hard either.
Fujimoto-san can smile like that?
All right, see you.
What a childish act.
He’s taken a liking to you, Kobato-chan.
Really… Fujimoto-kun and that person just won’t be honest with themselves…
That person?
Kobato-chan, thanks for your work today.
Let’s continue setting up the bazaar tomorrow.
Who’s “that person?”
Sayaka-sensei’s husband?
I'm pretty sure I took your order
for your husband's birthday cake.
Uh, yeah.
Could be.
“That person” isn’t honest with himself…
What kind of person was he?
Dunno.
What a mystery.
Not as much of a mystery as your drawing, Dobato!
That’s so mean!
Thank you so much, everyone!
What are these?
They’re teru teru bozu!
Teru teru bozu?
You hang those up in hopes that the weather will get better!
Who brought those?
Naomi-chan, you made those?
Yeah.
The teru teru bozu I make turn the weather sunny.
It was sunny when we went on our trip and went to the pool.
Those are amazing teru teru bozus!
I wonder if they’ll sell.
Yes!
I’ll make something too!
Let’s put them together and sell them!
Yeah!
Then let’s put price tags on everything.
Here.
Kobato-chan.
What is it?
If we sell a lot of teru teru bozu,
will we get to keep the preschool?
Yes, it’ll be all right!
To tell you the truth, my mom said…
She’s going to have a baby soon!
Really?
Congratulations!
So…
Mom is on vacation starting this month,
but she said she’s going back to work when the baby gets a bit bigger.
Then she said she wants Yomogi Preschool to take care of it too!
And then, I’ll be the older sister, so I’ll pick her up from the preschool!
That way I’ll be able to see Sayaka-sensei and you every day!
I want to see you every day as an older sister too, Naomi-chan!
Everyone, let’s do our best!
Yeah!
It really got late, didn’t it?
Are you from Yomogi Preschool?
Yes.
Judging by your voice, are you the one who picked up the phone earlier?
You’re…
The debt collector.
I’m going to crush the school.
Her loan will not be extended any further.
That was you on the phone…?
Overtime?
No!
The time passed while I was putting up the posters for the bazaar…
You’re a bad person, so I can’t tell you!
You’re an interesting girl.
I thought so on the phone as well.
Did you tell Sayaka that I wouldn’t extend the payment deadline?
Tell her that I stopped by today too.
When the deadline comes,
I’ll be taking down the preschool.
You can’t!
Even if the children are here.
If you don’t want anyone hurt, you’d better vacate soon.
See you later, Kobato-chan.
Taking down the preschool?
Is he serious?
It’s so cruel to not care about the children.
He has such a kind-looking face, but that man was really scary somehow.
That man? Who was it?
F-Fujimoto-san! Were you listening?
When you talk to yourself
that loudly, of course I’d hear.
I wasn’t talking to myse-
Who was it?
I didn’t ask him his name.
He was smiling a lot…
And he just called Sayaka-sensei, “Sayaka”…
Okiura, huh?
You know him?
Did he meet Sayaka-sensei?
N-No… He left after we spoke for a while.
Don’t tell Sayaka-sensei that he came.
But…!
Just stay quiet about it.
What did you come for?
I won’t forgive you if you
make Sayaka-san cry any more.
Got it?
Don’t show your face to Sayaka-san!
That man…
His name’s Okiura, right?
What relation does he have with Sayaka-sensei?
Isn’t that freaking obvious?!
He has the same surname as
the one who married Sayaka.
And he just calls her Sayaka.
Then, that man is Sayaka-sensei’s husband?!
Then why is he trying to take down the preschool?
You shouldn’t get yourself involved in this one.
You’ve got something else to do besides that, don’t you?
If you don’t fill the bottle, you won’t be able to go that place you want to go!
But… I’m worried.
What have you been sewing?
A mascot!
I’ve been sewing it with the cloth Chitose-san gave me!
Is that a penguin?
It’s a rabbit…
Are those supposed to be ears?!
It doesn’t matter if it’s a penguin or whatever!
I’ll work hard to make sure the bazaar is a success!
Are you going to make more of those mysterious lifeforms?!
You’re saying the same things as Fujimoto-san! So mean!
It’s getting really dark and cloudy.
It’ll be okay.
I’m sure it’ll get sunny.
I hope so.
Ioryogi-san?
I’ll bring something that’ll really sell.
Thank you!
Let’s do our best today!
Okay!
I’m sure the teru teru bozu will give us good weather.
Right!
Kobato-chan, don’t fall over!
We’re selling drinks too.
II won’t fall over!
You will.
I said I won’t, so I won’t!
You two sure get along.
No, we don’t.
Yeah!
Oh, that… Fujimoto-san got it from his part-time.
Thank you…
I knew you’d fall over.
I’m sorry…
Don’t get too excited.
I better hurry!
I knew you’d fall over, Kobato-chan.
Customers aren’t coming.
We even put up all those posters…
It’ll be all right.
Your parents will come later, but I’m sure other customers will come too.
Really?
I don’t think anyone will come like this.
This happened because I said we should have a bazaar…
Hello.
Chitose!
I heard from Kobato-san, so we came over.
Right?
Yeah!
Would you like some yakisoba?
We have iced coffee too!
We can make you a cafe au lait!
Thank you for coming!
Chiho and Chise were really looking forward to it too.
But…
When I looked today, the posters were gone,
so I was worried that it’d been cancelled.
That can’t be…
Don’t tell me he did that…
Kobato-chan?
I’m going to tell everyone that the bazaar isn’t cancelled!
It’s too late for that!
It’s not too late!
They might come still!
Even so…
We can’t have a bazaar like this.
But I want as many people as possible to come!
After all, after all… we all worked so hard for this!
All of us, together!
Kobato-chan…
Fujimoto-san, you did too!
Kobato-san’s such a good girl.
She really is.
Fujimoto-kun?
She went out calling for people, so I’m going to make the coffee.
He’s not very open, but he’s a good boy.
Yes.
A chicken?
A sunfish?
Nobody’s coming, after all.
The rain’s let up, and it’s getting sunny too…
Hello.
Is this the bazaar?
Yes.
Kobato-san came over to tell me the news.
So I’ve come to take a peek.
Oh, is this it?
I hear you’re having a bazaar?
Are there any good bargains here?
I’m looking forward to it!
Yeah. Where should we start?
Welcome!
Would you like some yakisoba?
Things are looking good here.
Doumoto.
Kobato-chan came to tell me.
Where’s Kobato-chan? She’s not back yet?
A cup of iced coffee, please.
Okay!
Kiyokazu-sensei, iced coffee!
Here you go.
Well, some energetic girl is going around,
shouting “Come to the Yomogi Preschool Bazaar!”
She seemed to be really desperate,
so I found myself saying “Okay then, I’ll check it out later!”
and then she came and shook my hands a whole lot.
Thank you so much!
I can certainly see her doing that. That’s so like Kobato-chan.
Mom!
Naomi, sorry for being late.
You’ve got a lot of customers.
Yeah.
It’s great that the weather cleared up.
Yeah!
There’s a bazaar at Yomogi Preschool!
Everyone, please come!